Guide to the Herbert Isaac Winer Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Herbert Isaac Winer papers
1911-2014
MS 1160
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
29.75
(70 boxes)
The papers of Herbert Isaac Winer include material related to Dr. Winer's teaching at the Yale Forestry School (later Yale School of Forestry and Environmental Studies), including course files, student files, correspondence, and class trips to the Yale Forestry Camp in Crossett, Arkansas. Research files consist of field data and statistical studies of logging and sawmill operations in the southern United States, especially in Crossett and Urania, Louisiana. The papers include data sheets, statistics, graphs, camp logs and reports, maps, and similar papers, many of them compiled by Winer. They are divided into studies of Urania, Crossett, and general mill studies and field data, and have been arranged chronologically within each division. Outside of Yale University, the papers include research files from Winer's employment at the Pulp and Paper Research Institute of Canada (1964-78) and the Mead Corporation (1979-1988). Further material includes files from Winer's forestry consulting work, various forestry related journals and publications collected by Winer for research, course work, or personal use, and personal files after his retirement from teaching in 1996.
Winer, Herbert Isaac
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Elwood Maunder, 1968 and Herbert I. Winer, 2000, 2004, 2012, and 2018.
Scope and Contents
The papers of Herbert Isaac Winer include material related to Dr. Winer's teaching at the Yale Forestry School (later Yale School of Forestry and Environmental Studies), including course files, student files, correspondence, and class trips to the Yale Forestry Camp in Crossett, Arkansas. Research files consist of field data and statistical studies of logging and sawmill operations in the southern United States, especially in Crossett and Urania, Louisiana. The papers include data sheets, statistics, graphs, camp logs and reports, maps, and similar papers, many of them compiled by Winer. They are divided into studies of Urania, Crossett, and general mill studies and field data, and have been arranged chronologically within each division. Outside of Yale University, the papers include research files from Winer's employment at the Pulp and Paper Research Institute of Canada (1964-78) and the Mead Corporation (1979-1988). Further material includes files from Winer's forestry consulting work, various forestry related journals and publications collected by Winer for research, course work, or personal use, and personal files after his retirement from teaching in 1996.
Biographical / Historical
Herbert Isaac Winer received a BA from Yale University in 1942. Following military service during World War II, he returned to the university and earned a PhD in forestry in 1956. He served as an instructor in forestry, 1952-1956, and as an assistant professor of logging, 1956-1963. He held several positions in logging research with the Pulp and Paper Research Institute of Canada, from 1964-1978, and with the Mead Corporation in Dayton, Ohio, from 1979-1988. Winer served as president of the Forest History Society, 1987-1989. In 1988 Winer returned to Yale to serve as a lecturer at the School of Forestry and Environmental Studies until his retirement from teaching in 1996.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged by accession.
Conditions Governing Access
Administrative records are restricted until 2039 as established by Yale Corporation regulations. http://web.library.yale.edu/mssa/collections/research-use-of-yale-university-archives.
Student records are restricted until 2076 as established by Yale Corporation regulations. http://web.library.yale.edu/mssa/collections/research-use-of-yale-university-archives. Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy of non-commercially produced items for their personal use should consult the ordering reproductions information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site. Original born digital files, as well as preservation masters, may not be accessed due to their fragility. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist request that they be made. Born digital files cannot be accessed remotely. System requirements include a Manuscripts and Archives computer and file viewing software.
Conservation of natural resources; Environmental protection; Forests and forestry; Logging -- Statistics; Sawmills -- Statistics; Crossett (Ark.); Urania (La.); Foresters; Winer, Herbert Isaac; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University. School of Forestry. Yale Forestry Camp
- Inventory, 1940-1962; 4.5 feet linear (11 boxes)
  - Urania, Louisiana
    - Grade recovery tallies, pine and hardwood, 1940-1942 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Logging field data, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Crossett, Arkansas
    - Logging, 1946-1947, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 3-5)
    - Mill, 1947, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 6-7)
  - Southern logging and sawmill field data
    - Sawmill studies
      - Mill data, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Live sawing, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - Turning, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - Pulpwood, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - Graphs, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - Log grades
        - 1, 2, 4, logs, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 13)
        - 3, 6-7, 14" logs, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 14)
        - 3A; diagrams and tallies, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 15)
        - 3B; diagrams and tallies, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 16)
        - Suspended; diagrams and tallies, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 17)
        - Computations, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 18)
        - Graphs and tables, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 19)
      - Felling and bucking, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 20)
      - Skidding, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 21)
      - Loading and hauling, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 22)
      - Machine rates, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 23)
      - Graphs, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 24)
      - Grade recovery, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 25)
      - Sawmill data and computations, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 26)
      - Quality control, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 27)
      - Sawmill data, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 28)
      - Quality control, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 29)
      - Pulp wood, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 30)
      - Grade recovery and quality control, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 31)
      - Grade recovery and quality control, 1959-1962 (Box 6, Folder 32-36)
      - Felling and bucking, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 37)
      - Surplus. dittos, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Field data
      - J.E. Blankinship operation, 1953-1955 (Box 7, Folder 39-42)
      - J.E. Blankinship operation, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 43-45)
      - James Henderson operation, 1953, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 46-51)
      - Otto Klick operation, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 52-54)
      - W.R. Blankinship operation, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 55-56)
      - W.R. Blankinship operation, 1957-1961 (Box 10, Folder 57-62)
      - Dent operation, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 63)
      - Ed Jenkins operation, 1960 (Box 11, Folder 64-66)
- Additional Material, 1957-1965; Accession 2000-M-121
  Scope and Contents
  Inventory
  - Yale Forestry Camp, Crossett, Arkansas
    - Logging studies [group computations, etc.], 1957-1965 (Box 1)
    - Mill studies, 1953-1959 (Box 2)
- Additional Material, 1970; Accession 2004-M-099
  - Logging Operations in the Practice of Forestry: Some Problems and Prospects, by Herbert I Winer [collection of three lectures, third of annual series of U. S. Plywood-Champion Papers Lectures delivered at the Yale School of Forestry and Environmental Studies], 1970 March 30-April 3 (Box 1)
- Additional Material, 1946-1996; Accession 2011-M-086
  - Morphology of the Fungi, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Plant Morphology, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Surveying, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Silviculture reports, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Crossett Logging studies, 1953-1956 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Crossett Mills studies, 1960-1965 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Selected topical references, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Forest Resource Management and Rural Development, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Log and notes, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Additional Material, 1949-1954; Accession 2012-M-054
  - Crossett camp log, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Crosett logging report, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Field study notes, Crossett lumber camp, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Syllabi and notes, 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Additional Material, 1911-2014; Accessions 2018-M-0001, 2018-M-0004; 20.52; (48 boxes)
  The accession includes Accessions 2018-M-0001 and 2018-M-0004 and consists of material related to Herbert Winer's teaching at the Yale Forestry School (later Yale School of Forestry and Environmental Studies), including course files, student files, correspondence, and class trips to the Yale campsite at Crossett, Arkansas. The accession also includes research files from Winer's employment outside of Yale at the Pulp and Paper Research Institute of Canada (1964-78) and the Mead Corporation (1979-1988). Further material includes files from Winer's forestry consulting work, various forestry related journals and publications collected by Winer for research, course work, or personal use, and personal files after his retirement from teaching in 1996.
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research.
  Administrative records are restricted until 2039 as established by Yale Corporation regulations. http://web.library.yale.edu/mssa/collections/research-use-of-yale-university-archives.
  Student records are restricted until 2076 as established by Yale Corporation regulations. http://web.library.yale.edu/mssa/collections/research-use-of-yale-university-archives.
  Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy of non-commercially produced items for their personal use should consult the ordering reproductions information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
  Original born digital files, as well as preservation masters, may not be accessed due to their fragility. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist request that they be made. Born digital files cannot be accessed remotely. System requirements include a Manuscripts and Archives computer and file viewing software.
  Arrangement
  The material is divided into four groupings: research files, Yale University files, personal and post-retirement files, and photographs and slides.
  - Research files, 1940s-2000
    - Consulting files
      - The Connecticut Research Conservation & Development Forestry Committee, 1989–1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence
        - Atkinson, David, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 2)
        - Berard, Jean, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 3)
        - Black, Jean Thomas, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - Clark, Janice, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 5)
        - Ewing, John, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 6)
        - Hair, Dwight, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 7)
        - Heard, Keith, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 8)
        - Howard, Andrew, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 9)
        - Kellogg, Loren, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 10)
        - Miller, Richard, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 11)
        - Page, Andrew, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 12)
        - Stuart, W.B., 1993–1996 (Box 1, Folder 13)
        - Ticknor, William D. III, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 14)
        - Wallinger, Scott, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Forest Engineering Research Institute of Canada, 1977–1991 (Box 1, Folder 16-17)
      - Georgia-Pacific Company, 1992–1995 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - Industrial Economics Incorporated, 1989–1990 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - Industrial Economics Incorporated, 1989–1990 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Irland Group, 1987–1989 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - McDonald Group, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Memo, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Mississippi State University review of Department of Forest Resources, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - North Louisiana Group of Foresters training session, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Nova Scotia Woodlot Owners and Operators Association, 1990–1992 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - Order of Quebec Forestry Engineers, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Rice Lumber Company talk, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Rossi Corporation vs. Perschel Forest Management, 1987–1991 (Box 3, Folder 2-3)
      - Shambon, Leonard, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - University of Guyana, 1990–1991 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - West Vaco, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - William Rolick vs. Collins Pine Company, 1988–1992 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Literature
      - Cartography, circa 1990s (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Forestry advertisements, circa 1980s (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - Forestry articles and publications, 1950s-1990s (Box 4, Folder 3-6)
      - Forestry articles and publications, 1950s-1990s (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
      - Forestry journals, studies, and reports, 1970s-1980s (Box 5, Folder 3-4)
      - Forestry journals, studies, and reports, 1970s-1980s (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - John Stevenson article on timber harvesting, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - U.S. Department of Agriculture publications, 1980s-1990s (Box 6, Folder 3-6)
    - Organizational files
      - American Pulpwood Association
        - Clemson short course on pulpwood production, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 1)
        - General files, 1987–1989 (Box 7, Folder 2-3)
      - The British Library, circa 1990s (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Forest Engineering Research Institute of Canada
        - Building dedication, 1994–1995 (Box 7, Folder 5)
        - Renewable energy symposium, 1976–1977 (Box 7, Folder 6)
        - Reports, 1977–2000 (Box 7, Folder 7-8)
      - Forest History Society
        - Administrative files, 1965–1968 (Box 8, Folder 1)
        - Administrative files, 1976–1981 (Box 8, Folder 2-4)
        - Administrative files, 1986–1991 (Box 8, Folder 5-6)
        - Administrative files, 1986–1991 (Box 9, Folder 1)
        - Affiliation with Yale, 1963–1968 (Box 9, Folder 2-3)
        - Articles of Incorporation, 1955- (Box 9, Folder 4)
        - Board Meeting, Harvard University, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 5)
        - Board Meeting, Washington D.C., 1961 (Box 9, Folder 6)
        - Collier Award, 1987–1989 (Box 9, Folder 7)
        - Correspondence, 1952–1965 (Box 9, Folder 8)
        - Correspondence, 1966–1968 (Box 10, Folder 1-3)
        - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 4)
        - Correspondence, 1976–1981 (Box 10, Folder 5-6)
        - Correspondence, 1976–1981 (Box 11, Folder 1)
        - Correspondence, 1987–1990 (Box 11, Folder 2-5)
        - Financial, 1985–1990 (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
        - Log, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 3)
        - Long Range Goals, 1988–1989 (Box 12, Folder 4-5)
        - Long Range Planning Committee, 1976–1981 (Box 12, Folder 6-7)
        - Memorandums, 1987–1990 (Box 13, Folder 1)
        - Photographs, circa 1989 (Box 13, Folder 2)
        - Publications, 1954–1971 (Box 13, Folder 3)
        - Resources, 1988–1990 (Box 13, Folder 4-5)
      - Forest Policy Center, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 6)
      - Journal of Forestry, 1961–1981 (Box 13, Folder 7)
      - Northern Journal of Applied Forestry, 1980–1984 (Box 13, Folder 8)
      - Northern Journal of Applied Forestry, 1988–1990 (Box 13, Folder 9)
      - Northern Journal of Applied Forestry, 1988–1990 (Box 14, Folder 1-3)
      - Mead Corporation
        - Columbus, Georgia files, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 4)
        - Correspondence, 1979–1988 (Box 14, Folder 5)
        - Correspondence with Robin Berlyn, 1979–1984 (Box 14, Folder 6)
        - Forestry and Harvesting Trainer Center, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 7)
        - History, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 1)
        - Kingsport Cruise Estimates, 1981–1984 (Box 15, Folder 2)
        - Manfor Ltd., Manitoba, 1984–1985 (Box 15, Folder 3-4)
        - Mississippi State University Harvesting Report, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 5)
        - Mississippi State University Logging Research Planning, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 6)
        - Post-employment, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 7)
        - Robert Karasek research, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 8)
        - Woodlands info, 1979–1980 (Box 15, Folder 9)
        - Woodlands managers meeting, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 10)
      - Midwest Mensurationists, 1979–1980 (Box 15, Folder 11-12)
      - North American Horse and Mule Loggers Association, 1995 (Box 15, Folder 13)
      - Peterson Pacific Corporation, 1995 (Box 15, Folder 14)
      - Pulp and Paper Research Institute of Canada
        - Annual Meeting, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 1-2)
        - Bowaters, Newfoundland, 1969–1970 (Box 16, Folder 3)
        - Conference on the history of the forest products industries, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 4)
        - Correspondence, general, 1964–1978 (Box 16, Folder 5)
        - Correspondence, David M. Smith, 1964–1978 (Box 16, Folder 6)
        - Correspondence, Eliott Katz, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 7)
        - Correspondence, George Garratt, 1964–1971 (Box 16, Folder 8)
        - Correspondence, John G. Garner, 1976–1978 (Box 16, Folder 9)
        - Forestry Comission Bulletin, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 1)
        - Great Lakes Paper Company, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 2)
        - Harvesting, 1960–1967 (Box 17, Folder 3)
        - J.J. Jehring articles, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 4)
        - Logging and Research Division, 1971–1974 (Box 17, Folder 5)
        - Logging Section Policy Notebook, 1965–1974 (Box 17, Folder 6)
        - McLennan library, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 7)
        - Measurement of Environment, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 8)
        - Nova Scotia files, 1969–1971 (Box 17, Folder 9)
        - Orpana, Robert files, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 1)
        - Pennsylvania State University job search, 1976–1977 (Box 18, Folder 2)
        - Productivity of Beliot Harvesters Operated by Domtar Woodlands Limited, 1969 (Box 18, Folder 3)
        - Publications, 1969–1988 (Box 18, Folder 4-5)
        - Sweden publications, 1955–1957 (Box 47, Folder 1)
        - Sweden visit, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 6-7)
        - Various literature, 1964–1978 (Box 19, Folder 1-2)
      - Seventh American Forest Congress, 1996 (Box 19, Folder 3)
      - Society of American Foresters, 1970–1983 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Writings
      - Articles and book reviews, 1940s-1990s (Box 19, Folder 5-7)
      - Bigelow Pond Stand, 1956 (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - Ethics and the Environment, 1989 (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - Forestry Handbook Review, 1956 (Box 20, Folder 3)
      - Log Sorting article, 1959–1960 (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - Logging Operations in Forestry: Some Problems and Prospects, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 5)
      - Louisiana State University symposium, 1961–1962 (Box 20, Folder 6)
      - Multi-product Logging, 1960–1961 (Box 20, Folder 7)
      - Reports, 1971–1980 (Box 20, Folder 8)
      - Seventh Northeastern Loggers Congress paper and talk, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Yale University files, 1940s-2004
    Yale University related files are restricted until 2039 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
    Student records are restricted until 2076 as established by Yale Corporation regulations. http://web.library.yale.edu/mssa/collections/research-use-of-yale-university-archives
    - Yale School of Forestry and Environmental Studies
      - Administrative records
        http://web.library.yale.edu/mssa/collections/research-use-of-yale-university-archives
        - 50th anniversary brochure with gallery prints, 1950 (Box 21, Folder 1)
        - 60th anniversary committee, 1957–1960 (Box 21, Folder 2-4)
        - Administrative talks, 1955–1963 (Box 21, Folder 5)
        - Alumni association, 1961 (Box 21, Folder 6)
        - Bangladesh internship program, 1981 (Box 21, Folder 7)
        - Best Management Practices for the Protection of Wetlands and Water Courses, 1996 (Box 21, Folder 8)
        - Building on a Century of Leadership, compact disc, 2002; 1 (Box 48)
        - Building on the Conservation Legacy at Yale, compact disc, 2004; 1 (Box 49)
        - Bursary file, 1954–1964 (Box 21, Folder 9)
        - Calendar and notes, 1990–1993 (Box 21, Folder 10)
        - Career stats, 1986–1987 (Box 22, Folder 1)
        - Case statement, 1975–1989 (Box 22, Folder 2)
        - Centennial history
          - Edith MacMullen files, 1990–2002 (Box 22, Folder 3-7)
          - Exploratory research and literature, 1990–2002 (Box 23, Folder 1)
          - Monthly financials, 1990–1997 (Box 23, Folder 2)
        - Committee on Marginalia and Curiosa, 1952–1963 (Box 23, Folder 3)
        - Committee on Reproducing Equipment, 1955 (Box 23, Folder 4)
        - Committee on Seminar Programs, 1961 (Box 23, Folder 5)
        - Correspondence, 1949-1964
          - A-G, 1949–1964 (Box 23, Folder 6)
          - H, 1949–1964 (Box 23, Folder 7)
          - I-J, 1949–1964 (Box 23, Folder 8)
          - K, 1949–1964 (Box 23, Folder 9)
          - L, 1949–1964 (Box 24, Folder 1-2)
          - M, 1949–1964 (Box 24, Folder 3)
          - R-S, 1949–1964 (Box 24, Folder 4)
        - Correspondence, 1980s-1990s
          - Arcudi, John, 1994 (Box 24, Folder 5)
          - Berlyn, Robin, 1990 (Box 24, Folder 6)
          - Cohon, Jared L., 1993–1997 (Box 24, Folder 7-8)
          - Gordon, John, 1988 (Box 24, Folder 9)
          - Kellert, Stephen R., 1988–1989 (Box 24, Folder 10)
          - Lawson, Thomas, 1994 (Box 24, Folder 11)
          - Loucks Jr, Vernon R., 1992 (Box 24, Folder 12)
          - Orentas, Narija, 1995 (Box 24, Folder 13)
          - Page, Alan C., 1995–1997 (Box 24, Folder 14)
          - Porterfield, Richard, 1994 (Box 24, Folder 15)
          - Samset, Ivar, 1990 (Box 25, Folder 1)
          - Sloman, Richard D., 1995 (Box 25, Folder 2)
          - Smith, David M., 1988 (Box 25, Folder 3)
          - Sundberg, Ulf, 1990 (Box 25, Folder 4)
          - Thank you letters, 1996 (Box 25, Folder 5)
          - Weetman, Gordon, 1988–1994 (Box 25, Folder 6)
          - Whitney, Gordon, 1989 (Box 25, Folder 7)
          - Winks, Robin, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 8)
          - Zettergren, Jane, 1995 (Box 25, Folder 9)
        - Course expo, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 10)
        - Curriculum, 1953–1962 (Box 25, Folder 11)
        - Curriculum Vitae, 1997 (Box 25, Folder 12)
        - Doctoral research conference, 1997 (Box 25, Folder 13)
        - Educational philosophy, 1954–1965 (Box 25, Folder 14)
        - Faculty meetings, 1988–1989 (Box 25, Folder 15)
        - Faculty memos, 1953–1960 (Box 25, Folder 16)
        - Fees and expenses, 1989–1996 (Box 25, Folder 17)
        - General files, 1960s-1970s (Box 26, Folder 1)
        - Graves lectures, 1988 (Box 26, Folder 2)
        - Graves library guide, 1959 (Box 26, Folder 3)
        - Guest speaker schedules, 1991 (Box 26, Folder 4)
        - Heraldry, 1963–1964 (Box 26, Folder 5)
        - History, 1954 (Box 26, Folder 6)
        - Industrial forestry, 1958 (Box 26, Folder 7)
        - J.P. Weyerhaeuser Timber Company, 1953 (Box 26, Folder 8)
        - Levin, Richard C. visit, 1993 (Box 26, Folder 9)
        - Library Policy Statement, 1953–1956 (Box 26, Folder 10)
        - Log, 1981–1988 (Box 26, Folder 11)
        - Long Bell Lumber Company, 1957–1961 (Box 26, Folder 12)
        - Management candidates, 1962–1963 (Box 26, Folder 13)
        - Management committee, 1988–1989 (Box 26, Folder 14)
        - Memorabilia, 1960–1964 (Box 26, Folder 15)
        - Memos, 1988 (Box 26, Folder 16)
        - News and Publications, 1960–1994 (Box 27, Folder 1-2)
        - Norfolk mill tour, 1961 (Box 27, Folder 3)
        - Northeastern Forest Tree Improvement Conference and World Forestry Conference, 1960 (Box 27, Folder 4)
        - Notes, 1960–1963 (Box 27, Folder 5)
        - OTF administration, 1964–1965 (Box 27, Folder 6)